ELISIA WRIGHT



Email: elisiawright234@gmail.com **Website:** elisiawright.com



+1 (609) 630-3178



232 Rivers Farm Road West Burke, VT 05871 Named **one of the top 60 undergraduate researchers** in the United States.

My research has been **presented to US Congress** and at **various prestigious conferences**.

My passion is helping to find practical solutions for environmental challenges through artificial intelligence and computational sustainability.

EDUCATION

Allegheny College, Meadville, PA Cumulative GPA: 3.28/4.00 Expected Graduation: 05/2021

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science, Environmental Science and Sustainability

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- JavaScript, Python, Java, HTML, CSS, Go, C++, COBOL, C
- Git, Netlify, Travis CI, Docker, Jenkins, Gatsby, Jekyll, Bootstrap, React

RECOGNITIONS

- One of the top 60 undergraduate researchers in the United States (Posters on the Hill 2019)
- Outstanding Achievement in Research Award (The Council on Undergraduate Research)
- PERC Campus Sustainability
 Champion Award (Pennsylvania
 Environmental Resource Consortium
 Executive Committee)
- Black Excellence Award (Association for the Advancement of Black Culture)
- Intel 2020 Scholarship (UNCF, Intel Corporation)
- Research has been featured in: The Washington Times, USA Today, Environmental Monitor Magazine, Allegheny Magazine, Erie-Times News

ACTIVITIES

- Founding charter member, Tamias and Phylacter of the Pi Phi Chapter of Zeta Phi Beta Sorority, Incorporated
- Volunteer Judge at Pennsylvania Junior Academy of Science
- **Social Media Chair** of the Green Students of Color Society

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer Intern – Intel Corporation

06/2020 - Present

Develop automated unit and integration testing for <u>Project Athena/Intel</u>
 Evo Platform and Intel vPro Platform

Allegheny Mozilla Fellow – Allegheny College

08/2019 - 03/2020

- Lead website developer
- Engineered tools and programs that integrate ethics into core curriculum
- TextMining research accepted to: PyCon 2020 (canceled due to COVID-19)

Computer Science Technical Leader – Allegheny College 08/2019 – 03/2020

- Assisted in class and laboratory sessions with instructional responsibilities
- Held office hours to effectively troubleshoot and resolve technical issues

Undergraduate Research Fellow – Allegheny College 05/2019 – 08/2019

Conducted independent research under guidance of faculty advisor

Additional Work Experience Available Upon Request

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Senior Thesis: Improve Industrial Hemp Cultivation with a Smart IoT Soil Spectroscopy System

12/2019 - Present

Engineered a low-cost system to assist farmers with agricultural techniques,
 which utilizes artificial intelligence for soil analysis, to determine soil quality

An Intelligent Underwater Robotic Smart-Sensing System for Water Quality Testing

09/2018 - Present

- Engineered robot for predicting and analyzing water quality trends
- Presented at: The United States Congress (<u>Posters on the Hill 2019</u>) and The 32nd International Conference of the Florida Artificial Intelligence Research Society (FLAIRS-32)

Using Python and GitHub for Team Formation and Assessment

01/2019 - 05/2019

- Project supervisor of GatorGrouper web application development
- Presented at: PyCon 2019

Additional Research Experience Available Upon Request